<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Merritt Khaipho-Burch</title>
    <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Merritt Khaipho-Burch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://merkhaiburch.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teaching and Outreach</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Experience Science communication, education, and outreach are incredibly important to me. Because of this, I have volunteered and taught through numerous Cornell-affiliated organizations during the course of my PhD. These include:
Skills for Public Engagement (PLSCI 3940 - Cornell undergraduate/graduate class, guest speaker presenting the seed dispersal game) Expanding Your Horizons The Graduate Student School Outreach Program (GRASSHOPR) Freeville Elementary School Research and Education Activities for Community Teachers (REACT) Teaching Assistant for Plant Genetics (PLBRG 2250) Developed Course Materials I developed an activity called &amp;ldquo;Cabbages and their cousins: the dogs of the plant world&amp;rdquo; where students identify shared morphology between modern cabbages and their wild, undomesticated Brassica ancestor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zines</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/zines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/zines/</guid>
      <description>Zines are small circulation publications that typically include original or appropriated images and texts. I started creating zines for my scientific projects to hand out at conferences as mementos. My zines typically include an overview of my project, brief results, key takeaways, contact information, and my resume on the inner page. I hand out anywhere from 20-60 zines per conference, depending on my poster&amp;rsquo;s location and the size of the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the patterns of pleiotropy and its biological relevance in maize</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/publications/pleiotropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/publications/pleiotropy/</guid>
      <description>Short Summary: Pleiotropy is not common in maize Pleiotropy in crop plants is highly constrained by evolution Pleiotropy results may vary by population and trait type Abstract Pleiotropy - when a single gene controls two or more seemingly unrelated traits - has been shown to impact genes with effects on flowering time, leaf architecture, and inflorescence morphology in maize. However, the genome-wide impact of true biological pleiotropy across all maize phenotypes is largely unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The perils and promise of single-gene solutions to crop yield: extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/publications/yield/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/publications/yield/</guid>
      <description>Short Summary: Increasing crop yield is critical for global populations, yet many crop molecular biology studies are touted as yield breakthroughs without sufficient replication to evaluate field performance, slowing progress within plant breeding. Here we suggest guidelines for the community to rigorously test the effect of genes on crop yield. Abstract Agriculture relies on plant breeding and genetics to deliver the best crop varieties and agronomic practices that will deploy results across nearly a billion hectares of cropland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomic mapping of the modifiers of teosinte crossing barrier 1 (Tcb1)</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/publications/tcb1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/publications/tcb1/</guid>
      <description>Short Summary: Tcb1 is one of roughly 10 cross-incompatibility systems in maize. With QTL mapping we found 2 significant QTL that explained 16% and 17% of the phenotypic variation. Markers could be developed to introgress these loci into breeding programs. Abstract Pollen cross-contamination has been a major problem for maize breeders. Mechanical methods applied to avoid cross-contamination are largely ineffective and time-consuming. Cross incompatibility barriers are genetic factors involved in maize fertilization that can be used as an effective method to prevent pollen cross-contamination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictive breeding for maize: Making use of molecular phenotypes, machine learning, and physiological crop models</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/publications/predictive_breeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/publications/predictive_breeding/</guid>
      <description>Short Summary: The start of genomic prediction began with Meuwissen, Hayes, &amp;amp; Goddard 2011. Standard genomic selection models may benefit from additional information along the central dogma, or outside of it (i.e., expression, metabolites, microbiome). Incorporating crop growth models with genomic prediction may further enchance prediction models. Abstract Maize (Zea mays L.) has been a focus of scientific research and breeding for over a century. It is also one of the most economically important crops in the world, with a value of approximately US$50 billion per year in the United States alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limited contribution of transposable elements to regulatory adaptation in maize inbreds and hybrids</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/creations/te_expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/creations/te_expression/</guid>
      <description>Project Status: Ongoing Short Summary We developed an inbred and hybrid population from the maize NAM founders and collected RNAseq data from four different tissues. We developed a RNAseq quantification pipeline optimized towards highly repetitive, complex genomes. I am currently building models to quantify the scale of TE effects towards gene expression. Abstract Transposable elements (TEs) contribute to ~85% of the maize genome and have been shown to impact genome structure and gene regulation by rearranging, adding, disrupting, or silencing endogenous promoters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/blog/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/blog/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Intro Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;quot; attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the patterns of pleiotropy and its biological relevance in maize</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/creations/pleiotropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/creations/pleiotropy/</guid>
      <description>Project Status: Complete Short Summary: Pleiotropy is not common in maize Pleiotropy in crop plants is highly constrained by evolution Pleiotropy results may vary by population and trait type Abstract Pleiotropy - when a single gene controls two or more seemingly unrelated traits - has been shown to impact genes with effects on flowering time, leaf architecture, and inflorescence morphology in maize. However, the genome-wide impact of true biological pleiotropy across all maize phenotypes is largely unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The perils and promise of single-gene solutions to crop yield: extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence.</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/creations/yield_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/creations/yield_project/</guid>
      <description>Project Status: Under Revision Short Summary: Increasing crop yield is critical for global populations, yet many crop molecular biology studies are touted as yield breakthroughs without sufficient replication to evaluate field performance, slowing progress within plant breeding. Here we suggest guidelines for the community to rigorously test the effect of genes on crop yield. Abstract Agriculture relies on plant breeding and genetics to deliver the best crop varieties and agronomic practices that will deploy results across nearly a billion hectares of cropland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
