<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Communication on Merritt Khaipho-Burch</title>
    <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Communication on Merritt Khaipho-Burch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teaching and Outreach</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Experience Science communication, education, and outreach are incredibly important to me. Because of this, I have volunteered and taught through numerous Cornell-affiliated organizations during the course of my PhD. These include:
Skills for Public Engagement (PLSCI 3940 - Cornell undergraduate/graduate class, guest speaker presenting the seed dispersal game) Expanding Your Horizons The Graduate Student School Outreach Program (GRASSHOPR) Freeville Elementary School Research and Education Activities for Community Teachers (REACT) Teaching Assistant for Plant Genetics (PLBRG 2250) Developed Course Materials I developed an activity called &amp;ldquo;Cabbages and their cousins: the dogs of the plant world&amp;rdquo; where students identify shared morphology between modern cabbages and their wild, undomesticated Brassica ancestor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zines</title>
      <link>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/zines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merkhaiburch.github.io/projects/contributions/zines/</guid>
      <description>Zines are small circulation publications that typically include original or appropriated images and texts. I started creating zines for my scientific projects to hand out at conferences as mementos. My zines typically include an overview of my project, brief results, key takeaways, contact information, and my resume on the inner page. I hand out anywhere from 20-60 zines per conference, depending on my poster&amp;rsquo;s location and the size of the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
